我的名字叫奥利弗・奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友
To honor my friend's memory,
我只能伪装成另一个人
I must be someone else.
深切怀念托马斯・梅林
孝子
成为另一个存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
根据15号刑事诉讼程序
We would like to serve notice to the defense,
我想要向被告宣布
pursuant to rule of criminal procedure 15.
我希望能在你提出死刑前
I would like to have a conversation with you
和你进行一次谈话
before you seek the death penalty.
莫伊拉  你隐瞒了什么
Moira, what don't I know?
有些事情
There are some things
永远不能提起
that must never be spoken of.
我输给他两次了  我不知道怎么阻止他
He's beaten me twice, and I don't know how to stop him.
你是谁
Who are you?
你一旦知道了  你的生活就要变样了
Once you know, your life will never be the same.
莎拉
Sara?
六年前
是啊  爸爸  大学很棒
Yeah, dad, college is great.
不  我和我的新室友很合得来
No, me and my new roommate totally hit it off.
我们是闺蜜
We're like besties.
好  爸爸  我得回化学实验室了
Ok. Yeah, dad, I got to get back to chem lab.
是啊  看来今晚的确很漫长
Yes. It looks like I got a long night ahead of me.
莎拉  挂断电话
Sara. Get off the phone!
好  爱你  老爸  再见
Ok. Love you, dad. Bye.
奥利
Ollie.
你真麻烦
You are trouble.
兰斯警探怎么样
How is Detective Lance?
他和往常一样  毫无头绪
Ah, he's clueless, as usual.
我好渴啊
Guess I was thirsty.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
1  2  3
1, 2, 3...
越来越近了
It's getting closer.
这么说可不太科学
That's not very scientific.
你还懂科学呀
And what would you know about science,
常春藤联盟辍学先生
Mr. Ivy League drop out?
我碰巧很了解科学
I happen to know a lot about science.
我知道  发酵
I know... fermentation.
我懂  生物
I know...biology.
劳蕾尔会宰了我的
Laurel's gonna kill me.
她真的会宰了我的
Oh, she's so gonna kill me.
你姐姐不会知道的
Your sister will never know.
来吧
Just come here.
这雷真够近的
Ok, that one was really close.
莎拉
Sara.
我们会没事的
We're going to be fine.
奥利弗
Oliver!
莎拉
Sara?
救命  救命
Help! Help!
莎拉
Sara!
奥利弗
Oliver!
睡不着吗
Can't sleep?
我不喜欢闭上眼睛
I don't do well with my eyes closed.
谢谢你让我住在这
Hey, thanks for letting me stay here.
我知道你在为你妈妈的事烦心
I know you got a lot going on with your mom.
西娅大部分时间住在她男友家  所以...
Thea's mostly staying at her boyfriend's. So...
别担心有人会发现你回来了
don't worry about anyone finding out that you're back.
谢谢你理解
Thanks for understanding.
我不理解
I don't understand.
你的家人每一天都在想你
You know, not a day goes by that your family doesn't miss you.
是吗  你怎么知道的
Yeah? How do you know?
因为我就想你
Because I missed you.
我觉得他们不会像你这么高兴见到我的
I don't think they'll be as happy to see me as you think.
你怎么可以那样说
How can you say that?
我知道当你离家很久时
I know how hard it is
要再回家是很困难的
to come home when you've been gone for so long.
我猜我爸爸和劳蕾尔
I'm guessing my father and Laurel
可不怎么高兴见到你
weren't too happy to see you.
一开始不高兴
No. No, not at first.
我不知道你和她复合没有
I wasn't sure if you and she ever got back together.
我们试过
We tried.
太难以承受了
It's too much.
我想有些事最好还是留在过去
I guess some things, you know, it's better left in the past.
我不等奎恩先生了  我们开始吧
I'm done waiting for Mr. Queen. Let's get started.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
有个老朋友来了城里
There's an old friend... in town.
我刚向你母亲和妹妹解释完
I just finished explaining to your mother and sister
兰斯小姐是检方的第二律师
that Miss Lance will be sitting second chair for the prosecution.
这有利益冲突
This is a conflict of interest.
兰斯小姐基本是在奎恩家长大的
Miss Lance practically grew up in the Queen house.
我觉得你这是在夸大事实
I think you're overstating matters.
等我把冲突人兰斯小姐移出这起案子再看吧
Oh, we'll see when I move to conflict Miss Lance off this case.
也许这很快就不是一起案子了
Maybe there won't be a case much longer.
我来这里不只是为了陪兰斯小姐
I come here not just with Miss Lance,
还带来了有条件认罪建议
but also with a plea offer.
终身监禁  可能保释
Life, with the possibility of parole.
不
No.
我们不认罪  奎恩女士是无辜的
We are not pleading out. Mrs. Queen is innocent.
她教唆了503起杀人案
She aided and abetted 503 homicides.
是在一个名叫马尔科姆・梅林的
Under duress from a homicidal maniac
杀人狂的强迫下做的
named Malcolm Merlyn.
她还在犯罪阴谋执行之前
She also withdrew from the criminal conspiracy
-抽身而退  -就早了五分钟
- prior to its execution. - Five minutes prior.
马尔科姆・梅林死了  陪审团
With Malcolm Merlyn dead, a jury's going
总要找到个替罪羊
to want to have to blame someone.
如果她不接受这笔交易
If she doesn't take the deal,
那她就可能被判处死刑
then she's facing the death penalty.
听起来很像敲诈
Sounds a lot like blackmail.
这是现实  还有更多...
Try reality. And here's some more--
我们得到你最近十年的手机短信
We've subpoenaed over a decades' worth of phone messages,
电话记录  信件和邮件
phone records, letters and emails.
我敢肯定我找到了一些信息
I'm willing to bet I find
能把你"受到强迫"的辩词驳得体无完肤
something that crushes your duress defense to powder.
唐纳先生
Mr. Donner...
如果你不介意的话
if you don't mind,
我想要几天时间来考虑你的提议
I'd like a few days to consider your offer.
当然可以
Of course.
先失陪了
Excuse me.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
劳蕾尔
Laurel?
车里见
I'll meet you at the car.
你要起诉我妈妈吗
You're prosecuting my mother?
这案子不是我要求的  而是分配给我的
I didn't ask for this case. I was assigned.
-那就拒绝啊  -这是份新工作  奥利弗
- So say no! - It's a new job, Oliver.
我没多大影响力  我仅有的影响力
I don't have a lot of pull. And what pull I do have,
也都用来帮你母亲搞那个认罪协议了
I used to get that plea bargain for your mother.
这是你的主意吗
This was your idea?
终身监禁
Life in prison?
地方检察官对死刑的事是认真的  奥利
The D.A. is serious about the death penalty, Ollie.
我们都知道失去一个人的感觉
We both know what it's like to lose someone.
好好想想  救救你妈的命
So think about it and save your mother's life.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
也许上周我没说清楚
In case I wasn't clear last week...
我不想再回答那个问题了
I'm done answering that question.
救命
Help!
这边
Over here!
莎拉
Sara?
Sara.
你没事吧
You OK?
你妈妈的事情进展怎么样了
How did everything go with your mother?
我遇到你姐姐了  她在负责这个案子
I ran into your sister. She's working on the case.
-你没告诉她...  -没有
- You didn't tell her... - No.
我理解为什么有时要保守秘密
I know a little something about keeping secrets
我也尊重这些秘密  尽管我...
and respecting them, even though I don't...
完全不明白为什么你要保守秘密
totally understand why you're keeping yours.
是不是
Is this--
是不是因为岛上发生的事
Is it because of what happened on the island?
不是
No.
是后来的事
After.
我做了一些事
There were things that I did;
为了生存不得不做的事
things that I had to do to survive.
无法原谅的事
Things that there's no forgiveness for.
说到原谅的话
Well, that's the thing about forgiveness--
你不请求原谅怎么得到原谅呢
you can't get it until you ask for it.
梅林
Merlyn?
你是什么人
Who are you?
只是个武士  跟你一样
Just a warrior. Like you.
你为什么穿得跟马尔科姆・梅林一样
Why are you dressed like Malcolm Merlyn?
谁派你来的
Huh? Who sent you?!
我还记得第一次看见这件兜帽服的时候
I remember the first time I saw this hood.
穿在莎朵的身上
Shado was wearing it.
这些就是你的装备总部了吧
This is quite the set-up that you got here.
你就在这里为了星城孤军奋战的
Where you're launching your one man war for Starling.
我不是孤军奋战
I'm not one man.
这是我的朋友
These are my friends.
约翰・狄格尔和费利西蒂・斯莫克
This is John Diggle and Felicity Smoak.
伙计们  这是莎拉
Guys. This is Sara.
欢迎回家  莎拉
Welcome home, Sara.
听到你没死的消息时我很高兴
I was happy to hear you're not dead anymore.
我是说  你第一次没死之前我不认识你
I mean, I didn't know you before you didn't die the first time.
很高兴你还活着
I'm still glad you're alive.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们刚刚在奎恩宅邸遇到一个不速之客
We just had an uninvited guest in the Queen mansion.
受过训练  武艺高超
Trained. Highly skilled.
而且他穿的跟梅林一样
And he was dressed like Merlyn.
我上次确认过  马尔科姆・梅林已经死亡
Well, the last I checked Malcolm Merlyn was dead,
一支利箭刺穿了他的心脏
courtesy of an arrow jammed through his heart.
不是他  那是个追随者
It wasn't him. It was a follower,
一个决心报复的下属  不管是什么人
an underling bent on revenge. Whoever it was...
他知道我是谁
He knows who I am.
天  我可没给过你一袋土
Gee, I didn't get you a bag of dirt.
我在宅子里发现的  山寨梅林带进来的
I found it in the house. Copycat Merlyn tracked it in.
你分析一下  希望能够帮我找到他
I want you to analyze it. Hopefully it'll lead me right to him.
然后呢
Then what?
如果这个冒牌货那么想追随马尔科姆・梅林
If this pretender wants to follow Malcolm Merlyn so badly,
那就追随他一起进坟墓吧
he can follow him right into a grave.
莎拉  我们会找到这家伙的
Sara? We'll find this guy.
我不想让你那么做
I don't want you to.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
他不是来找你的  奥利
He wasn't after you, Ollie.
他是来找我的
He's after me.
他是什么人
Who is he?
他被称作阿奥阿  "第一个"
He's called Al Qw-Al, "The First".
他是刺客联盟的成员
And he's a member of the League of Assassins.
等等  刺客联盟
Wait. Wait. The League of Assassins?
我还以为是虚构的呢
I thought they were a myth.
刺客联盟是什么  拜托
What's the League of Assassins? And please,
可别告诉我就是刺客组成的联盟
don't say it's a league made up of assassins.
不  这是个都市传奇
No, it's an urban legend.
我从阿富汗一个部落首领那里听说的
I heard about them in afghanistan from a tribal leader.
他号称有一个古老的刺客宗派
He claimed there was an ancient sect of assassins,
杀人如魔鬼  行踪似魑魅
deadly warriors that killed and vanished like ghosts.
我还以为他是抽嗨了不清醒才这么说的
Thought he was smoking what he was selling.
我想告诉你的  奥利  但你不听
I tried to tell you, Ollie, but you wouldn't listen.
那就是你过去四年待的地方
That's where you've been the past four years.
你学会战斗的地方
That's where you learned to fight.
你是他们的一员
You're one of them.
翻船之后  联盟一个成员救了我
After the freighter, a member of the league rescued me;
让我入伙并把我带去了南达尔巴特
took me in and brought me to Nanda Parbatt.
他们把我改造成了现在的样子
They remade me into what I am.
我发誓对他们效忠
And I swore them my allegiance.
那他们现在为什么翻箱倒柜想把你找出来
Why are they kicking down doors trying to find you now?
因为我离开了
Because I left.
想要离开联盟  只有一个方法
And there's only way that you leave the league.
这就是你不想见家人的原因吗
Is that why you didn't want to see your family?
一年前  我在圭亚那
A year ago, I was in Guyana.
我被派去处理一个叫苏亚雷斯的人
I was sent there for a man named Suarez.
他是当地的外交官
He was a local diplomat.
我割开了他的喉咙
And I slit his throat.
在他的床上
In his bed.
他的孩子们
And his kids...
他们第二天早上发现了他的尸体
They found his body in the morning.
我是个杀人犯  奥利
I'm a murderer, Ollie.
你觉得我的家人
You think that my family
见到我会觉得高兴吗
will be happy to see me?
西娅・奎恩
你在哪儿
我得去铁山监狱了
I have to go to Iron Heights.
费利西蒂  找到这个阿奥阿
Felicity, I need you to find this Al Ow-Al.
谢谢  谢谢你们
Thank you, thank you.
你为什么会在海上
What were you doing out there?
我原来在船上
The boat that I was on,
我们遇到暴风雨了
and we got caught in the storm.
-过来  -别  别  别
- Come - Wait, wait, wait, guys!
别  我  罗伯特・奎恩  罗伯特・奎恩
Wait! I--Robert Queen. Robert Queen.
是他的船
It was his boat, and--and--
他们很有钱
they are rich.
他会付钱给你们的  要多少给多少
He'll pay whatever you want, please!
求求你们
Please, please!
求求你们  别
Please, no!
求求你们
Please, please!
求求你们  别这样  别这么做
Please, no! No! You've made a mistake.
放我出去
Please let me out.
为什么不让我  别走  回来
Why won't you let me-- no, please, come back!
放我出去
Let me out!
你不是认真的吧
You cannot be serious!
-怎么了  -她想接受那份认罪协议
- What's going on here? - She wants to take the deal!
如果是因为死刑
Whoa! If this is about the death penalty...
我已经向你母亲解释过了
I've been explaining this to your mother.
即使真要审判
Even if we ever get to sentencing,
你也是被逼的  我完全可以
you were acting under duress. I have everything I need
打赢官司  不让你被判死刑
to keep them from sentencing you to death.
我并不怕死刑  简
The death penalty doesn't scare me, Jean.
那你为什么要放弃
Then why aren't you fighting?
-我自有我的理由  -说一个听听
- I have my reasons. - Name one.
因为我不想争取了
Because I'm tired of fighting.
我不认为我可以赢得陪审团的信任
I am not confident that I can win over a jury.
我也不觉得我配得上他们的信任
And I'm not altogether certain that I deserve to.
-这是三个理由了  -西娅
- That was actually three. - Thea...
别碰我  你真的就打算这么放弃了
No, seriously, you're just ready to give up?!
就准备好在这里终老了
Just take your medicine and spend the rest of your life in here.
我们还需要你
We still need you.
我还需要你
I still need you.
我真受不了了
I--I can't take this.
一直以来
Growing up...
我一直以为我们之间没有秘密
I didn't think that there were secrets kept between us.
去年我知道我错了
Last year I learned different.
而我也变得能够看清
And I've gotten pretty good
你有事对我隐瞒时的样子了
at knowing when you're hiding something from me.
妈妈
So, mom...
你现在在隐瞒什么
What are you hiding now?
让你妹妹接受我的决定
Help your sister come to terms with my choice,
因为我已经决定了
because it's made.
抱歉之前吓到你了
Sorry if I upset you before.
我们都有脱不清关系的人和事
We all join clubs we wish we hadn't.
我花了一年时间才退出那家健身房
It took me a year to get out of that gym membership.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢谢你让我觉得舒服
Not making me feel like what I am.
奥利弗很幸运能有你们两个朋友
Oliver's lucky to have you both as friends.
他之前一直交友不慎
He hasn't always had the best luck in that area.
-你妈妈的事怎么样了  -很不好
- How'd it go with your mother? - Not well.
你有找到人可以让我发泄一下吗
If you found somebody for me to hit yet?
也许吧  对你家里的泥土做的光谱分析
Could be. Spectro analysis of the dirt from your house
查出里面有碳醛
had trace amounts of aldicarb in them.
-那是什么  -一种杀虫剂
- What? - It's a pesticide.
星城以前有一家碳醛工厂
Starling city used to have its own aldicarb plant,
但是三年前环保署把它关了
but per the EPA, it was shut down three years ago.
那它现在作何用处
What's it being used for now?
什么都没  它被遗弃了
Nothing. It's abandoned.
我猜  它现在是刺客联盟派来的
But my guess is, it's the homebase
杀手的老巢
to one league of assassins assassin.
他会杀了你的
He will kill you.
和你一样  我也没那么容易死
Like you, I am not that easy to get rid of.
这是我的战斗
This is my fight.
从他闯进我家的那一刻起就是我的战斗了
He made it my fight when he came into my house.
从他威胁我所关心的人的那一刻起
And when he threatened somebody that I care about.
箭
Arrows.
这么没用的武器
Such an ineffective projectile.
现在怎么会还有人害怕它
I find it strange anyone who still fears them.
如果你继续纠缠莎拉・兰斯
I'll show you why--
你自然会知道为什么
if you don't leave Sara Lance alone.
这是唯一一次警告
This is your only warning.
你以为你威胁我
And it would be effective,
它就会变得有用了吗
were you to pose a threat to me.
你差点就输给了马尔科姆・梅林
You barely defeated Malcolm Merlyn
几乎用生命为代价才打赢他
at nearly the cost of your own life.
对上训练出他的人  你又有几分胜算
What hope would you have against the man who trained him?
我的胜算是我不是一个人
Hopes that I didn't come alone.
拉尔斯・艾尔・古尔之子正等着你回去
The child of Ra's Al Ghul awaits your return.
我不会回去的
I'm not going back.
这可由不得你
That's not your choice.
我受命带你回去
I have orders to return you...
不论死活
alive or dead.
你不会杀我的
You're not going to kill me.
你太高估你的重要性了
You overestimate your importance.
无论如何  你得跟我们回去
Regardless, you're coming back with us.
我们
Us?
和你一样  我也不是一个人
Like you, I did not come alone.
如果你不自愿回去
If you will not return willingly,
我们会毁了你的家人
we'll stay to bury your family.
你一点都没哆嗦
You're not even flinching when he...
几年前我就不怕疼了
Pain and I came to a little understanding few years back.
好了
Done.
刺客联盟
The league of assassins.
她为什么不告诉我这些年发生了什么
Why wouldn't she tell me what happened to her all those years?
也许和你不告诉我们
Probably the same reason why you didn't tell us
你在岛上遇到过什么的理由一样
what happened to you on the island.
我们要保护兰斯一家人
We need to protect the Lances.
我来保护劳蕾尔
I'll take Laurel.
我呢
What can I do?
什么都不做  你受伤了  就在这里待着
Nothing. You're hurt, and you need to stay here.
我爸怎么办
What about my father?
我会和兰斯警探谈的
I'll go talk to Detective Lance.
让他离开这里几天
Tell him he needs to get out town for a couple of days.
请不要告诉他我的事
Please don't tell him about me.
我能保密  问他就知道了
I can keep a secret. Just ask him.
你们三人的队伍可真好
You three are quite the team.
我们经历过一些事
We have our moments.
起来
Get up.
别  不要  求你们了
Wait, wait, no, no, please!
求你们了  不要
Please, please, no!
你越挣扎
The more you struggle...
就越痛
the more it'll hurt.
别这样  求你们了
No, no, please!
求你们了
Please!
住手
Wait.
放开她
Let her go.
你没资格命令我
You don't give me orders.
我没资格  但船长有
No, that would be the captain.
他现在听我指令行事
But he works for me.
是吧
Doesn't he?
救救我  求你了
Help me, please!
过来
Come here.
劳蕾尔  还是你老爸  听我说
Laurel, listen, it's your father--again.
我知道自从上周我让你停车
Ok, now listen, I know you're still mad at me
对你说了那番话之后你还在生我气
after what I said when you got pulled over last week,
但我们这样冷战是不对的
but it's not right, us not talking.
所以拜托你回我电话好吗
So please, just-- just call me, ok?
兰斯警探  我知道你已经下班
Detective Lance! I knew you'd be getting home around now
现在应该准备回家
because your shift has ended.
因为我黑了你的手机
Which I knew because I kind of pinged your cell phone.
斯莫克小姐
Miss Smoak.
你的工作给你带来了蟑螂[危机]
You have cockroaches and they mean business.
你什么时候开始上门服务的
Since when did you start making house calls?
因为你有危险
Since you're in danger.
我不怕蟑螂
I'm not afraid of cockroaches.
你现在真的很危险
Yes, you're in real danger!
你得离开星城几天
You need to get out of town for a couple days.
我一换上警服  就要面对危险
Listen, I'm in danger every time I put on this uniform,
所以你最好说得具体点
so you're going to have to be a little more specific.
有个叫做刺客联盟的组织
There's an organization called the League of Assassins
里面有三个成员要对付你
and three of its members are targeting you.
说出来感觉有点莫名其妙
It...sounded a little less crazy in my head.
我不信
I doubt it.
马尔科姆・梅林就是其中一员
Malcolm Merlyn was apparently a member.
我这样说  你大概能明白
That should give you some sort of idea
我们要面对的是什么角色了吧
about the type of people we're dealing with.
好  我相信你
Ok, I'll bite.
我究竟怎么惹到他们了
What did I do to piss them off?
这个嘛
That...um...
说来话长
is a really long story.
你只要  只要相信我就好
You just... you need to trust me.
你待在星城很不安全
You're not safe here in starling city.
斯莫克  在这里谁能安全呢
Smoak, nobody's safe, ok?
警察就更不可能了
Especially not us cops.
干的就是挨枪子的活儿
We get shot at for a living.
而我今天的活儿  刚结束
And my shift? It just ended.
-兰斯警探  -晚安
- Detective Lance! - Good-night.
等等  你得听我说啊
Wait, you need to listen to me!
晚安  斯莫克小姐
Good night, Miss Smoak.
这么说  你是不打算离开这里了
So I guess this means you're not leaving town?
晚上好
Evening.
我该早点告诉你的
I should have said this earlier,
我们俩不太适合
but it's not appropriate for us
谈论你妈妈的案件
to be discussing your mother's case.
我只是刚好在附近
Actually, I was in the neighborhood,
所以我想或许可以过来
so I thought that I would swing by
看看你要不要一起吃个饭
and see if I could give you a ride home and maybe
我再送你回家
get a bite to eat.
我今天很累了  我不想再听你
It's been a long day. I don't need an even longer night
长篇大论说服我别插手你母亲的案件
of you trying to talk me out of your mother's plea agreement.
劳蕾尔
Laurel.
我保证  这和我母亲的案子无关
I promise, this has nothing to do with my mother's case.
你这几周过得很辛苦
You've had a rough couple of weeks.
你确定不需要找个朋友陪陪
You really going to tell me you couldn't use a friend?
走吧
Come on.
-情况如何  -很糟糕
- How'd it go? - Badly.
他要么不相信我  要么以为我开玩笑
He either didn't believe me or didn't take me seriously.
现在想想  我或许不该提到
In hindsight, I probably shouldn't have led
刺客联盟
with League of Assassins.
现在怎么办
What do we do now?
你要干什么  奥利弗叫你待在这
What are you doing? Oliver told you to stay put.
你不是不希望你父亲知道你还活着么
I thought you didn't want your father to know you're still alive.
确实  但告诉他总比害死他好
I don't. But it's better than him not being.
-你又打算去哪儿  -跟你一起走
- Where do you think you're going? - With you.
我可不能让你孤身冒险
I'm not going to let you go out there without any back-up.
狄格  虽然你是经验丰富的特种兵
Dig, you may be a three tour special forces veteran,
但跟我所受过的训练相比
but I was trained by the people that make the special forces
就是大巫见小巫了  让开
look like a kindergarten class. So step aside
否则别怪我不客气
or get put down.
你这是去送死  莎拉
It's your funeral, Sara.
已经死过一回了
It wouldn't be my first.
不  这不可能
No, it can't be.
你不可能是莎拉
It can't be Sara.
是我  是莎拉
It's me. It's Sara.
爸爸
Daddy...
没事了
It's ok.
莎拉
Sara?
Sara!
这是你的茶  请问你还需要什么吗
不用了  谢谢
你会说中文了
You speak Chinese now?
这几年来学了不少东西
Picked up a couple things in the past few years.
是啊
Yes.
为什么不告诉我们  你还活着
Why didn't you let us know that you were alive?
我和你妈妈  我们...
I mean, your mother and I, we...
都很想念你
We missed you.
你姐姐也是
And your sister did, too.
你知道的吧
You know that, right?
我知道你们离婚了
I know you got divorced.
是啊
Yeah.
但这不是你的错
But it wasn't your fault.
是我的问题
That was on me.
问题因我而起
Because of me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系  一切都无关紧要  知道吗
It's all right. None of that matters now. You know why?
因为你回家了  宝贝  你回家了
'cause you're home, sweetie, you're home.
你有麻烦了吗
Are you in trouble?
不  爸爸
No, dad.
是你有麻烦了
You are.
是你让费利西蒂・斯莫克劝我离开星城的
You sent Felicity Smoak to warn me to leave town.
你认识绿箭侠
You know the Arrow.
你是那个蒙面女
You're the girl in the mask.
你一直在贫民区锄强扶弱
You've been kicking the crap out of creeps in the glades.
你已经回来好几周了
You've been home for weeks.
告诉我
Tell me something--
如果这些杀手  没有现身
If these assassins, if they hadn't shown up,
你是不是永远不会让我们知道你还活着
would you have ever let us know that you were alive?
是的
No.
费利西蒂说那些人是某个联盟的成员
Felicity said that these guys were part of a league of something.
他们想干什么
What do they want with you.
跟所有刺客一样  想干掉他们的目标
What all assassins want-- to terminate their objective.
真是荒谬
Oh, this is crazy.
父亲  我们该走了
Dad, we have to go.
不  我们哪里都不去
No, we are not going anywhere.
你坐下来详细地告诉我
Not until you sit down and you tell me exactly
你到底惹上了什么事
what you've gotten yourself into.
你是个出色的警察  而且你很坚强
You are an amazing cop and you are strong
很正派  很诚实
and decent and honest.
但这些人  他们能够
But these men, they will
不费吹灰之力就把你干掉
cut you down before you can lift a finger.
求你了  跟我一起走吧
Now please. Come with me.
虽然挺破的  但是...
I'm afraid it's not much, but, uh...
也算是个家
It's home.
为什么你要把门锁起来
Why did you lock the door?
不  不是那个意思
No, no, no, no. It's not because...
习惯而已  这里的船员们不是很友好
It's just a habit. My shipmates aren't exactly the nicest bunch.
请进来吧  随便坐
Please, come in. Have a seat.
我叫艾沃
My name is Ivo.
安东尼・艾沃博士
Dr. Anthony Ivo.
你的名字是
And you are?
莎拉
Sara.
很高兴见到你  莎拉
Nice to meet you, Sara.
你为什么把那些人锁在笼子里
Why do you keep those people down there in those cells?
那是我的工作  我需要他们
It's my work. I need them.
什么工作
What work?
我要拯救人类  莎拉
I am going to save the human race, Sara.
也许你能帮助我
Maybe you can help me.
我注意到你吃饭的时候没有喝酒
I noticed you didn't have a drink at dinner.
是的  我没喝
No. I didn't.
你现在愿不愿意承认  上周你以为我
So will you now admit that you and my father
又开始酗酒
overreacted last week
你和我父亲的反应有点过激了
when you thought that I was becoming a drunk?
我愿意承认我关心你
I am prepared to admit that I care about you.
所以你才坚持要送我到房间门口吗
Is that why you insisted on walking me to my door?
你真懂我
You know me.
我只是想确保你的安全
I just wanted to make sure you were safe.
这样才安全
This is safe.
这个
This...
我们不能这么做
We shouldn't.
那你为什么要陪着我走这么久
Then why did you come all the way up here?
很抱歉  我让你误会了我的意思
I'm really sorry if I was sending the wrong message.
不
No!
不  我知道你的意思
No, no, I got the message.
我每天都很清楚你的意思
I get it loud and clear every day.
快跑
Run.
快跑  远离劳蕾尔
Run, run away from Laurel,
越快越好
run as fast as you can.
-劳蕾尔  别这样  -莎拉
- Laurel, come on.  - Sara...
她和你一起上了"金牌奎恩号"
She got on "The gambit" With you.
我父亲  他
My father, he--
他躲进酒瓶里醉生梦死
He climbed into a bottle.
我母亲  她  她躲进车里
My mother, she--she climbed into her car
驶离了这个家  然后是汤米...
and she drove away, and then Tommy...
我做了什么  为什么所有人都要离开
What is so wrong with me that everybody leaves?
我永远不会离开你
I will never leave you.
你会离开的
Until you do.
我记得我锁了门
I thought I locked that.
待在这里
Stay here.
奥利
Ollie?
有什么状况吗
Anything?
一切正常
All good.
我得走了
I have to go.
听着  刚才说的话我很抱歉
Listen, I'm sorry about what I said--
不用道歉
Don't be.
待在这里别出去
Just stay here.
费利西蒂  阿奥阿来劳蕾尔的住处了
Felicity, Al Ow-al was at laurel's place.
什么  她没事吧
What? Is she ok?
她没事  看来他在我们到达之前离开了
She's fine. Looks like he moved out before we got there.
但是如果劳蕾尔不是他的目标
But if Laurel's not his target...
他的目标是兰斯  我需要他的地址
He's after Lance, and I need a location now.
我居然没想到应该来这里找你
Well, I can't believe I didn't think to look for you up here.
这里的视野很好  能看到整个城市
It's a good vantage point. You can see the whole city.
就像站在电线上的鸟
Like a bird on a wire.
我之前在的地方  要选择一个新名字
Where I was, they have you choose a new name.
我选的是塔尔・莎菲尔
I chose Ta-er Sah-fer.
是一个阿拉伯名字
It's Arabic.
意思是金丝雀
For canary.
你十岁的时候我给你买了那只金丝雀
I bought you that canary when you were ten.
我离家非常远
I was as far from home as you can get,
但我从未忘记家在哪里
but I never forgot where I came from.
有人说  忘记一个人
You know how they say the first thing
最先忘记的是他的声音
you forget about somebody when they're gone is their voice?
记得他们的脸
You can remember their face,
他们走路的姿势
and the way they move,
但却很难记得他们的声音
but you can't hold on to the way they sound.
我从未忘记过你的声音  父亲
I never forgot your voice, dad.
宝贝
Sweetheart...
我们没时间了
We're out of time.
所以  你希望你父亲死在这里
So, this is where you wanted your father to die.
怎么回事  莎拉  他们是什么人
What the hell, Sara, who are these guys?
我们是你女儿的同伴  兰斯警官
Associates of your daughter, Officer Kance.
她交朋友的品味一向很差
Well, she always did have the worst taste in friends.
你真的以为我们找不到你吗
Did you really think we weren't going to find you here?
当然不会
No.
我知道你们能找到
I knew you would.
动手
Go.
你应该多注意周围的环境
You should be mindful of your surroundings.
枪是懦夫的武器
Guns are a coward's weapon.
没有手枪你还会什么
What are you without your side arm?
会拿出备用枪
A guy with a spare.
你觉得  就因为你受宠
You think because you are the beloved
就能得到自由吗
you will be granted your freedom?
自由只有一种
There's only one freedom.
我来赋予你自由
Let me grant you yours.
你不必做这么绝
You don't have to do this.
-都结束了  -还没
- It's over! - Not yet.
莎拉  宝贝  不要
Sara, baby, don't...
告诉拉尔斯・艾尔・古尔
Tell Ra's Al Ghul
别惹我家人  有事冲着我来
that my family is off limits. His quarrel is with me.
抱歉让你看到这些
I'm sorry you saw that.
我不能想象你会怎么看待我
I can't imagine what you must think of me.
我觉得你是幸存者
I think you're a survivor.
你是我见过的最勇敢的人
I think you're one of the bravest people I've ever known.
你是我女儿
You're my daughter.
是时候回家了
It's time for you to come back home.
-我不能  -为什么
- I can't  - Why not?
他们不会停止寻找我
They are never going to stop looking for me.
我会保护你
I'll protect you.
我们会保护你
We'll protect you.
-告诉她留下来是安全的  -爸爸
- Tell her it's safe to stay.  - Dad...
如果他们伤害你  劳蕾尔或妈妈
If they hurt you or Laurel or mom,
那我也不活了
then I really would die.
但她们应该知道你还活着
But they need to know.
-不能告诉她们  爸爸  -为什么
- They can't. They can't, daddy. - Why not?
你知道原因  我回来是要确保家人安全
You know why! I came back to make sure that my family was safe,
你们现在都没事
and you are.
但如果她们知道我还活着
But if they knew I was alive,
劳蕾尔和妈妈
Laurel and mom,
她们会一直找我
they would never stop looking for me,
这会令她们都丧命
and that could get them both killed.
我不能放你走
I can't let you go.
I can't let you go!
我必须  爸爸  我必须走
I have to--dad, I have to--I have to go.
我爱你
I love you.
保护好他们
Keep them safe.
探长
Detective...
她说得对
She's right.
你必须为她保密
You have to keep her secret.
这是我遇到的最难做到的事
It's already the hardest thing I've ever had to do.
你都是怎么过这种日子的
How do you live like this?
我不介意孩子们来探视我
I never mind getting a visit from my children,
但我知道你们为什么而来
but I know why you're here.
我们只是想再说一件事
We just have one more thing to say.
奥利弗  我们已经说好了
Oliver, we've already been through this.
我不会改变主意的
I am not going to change my mind.
这次是我改变主意
This is about me changing mine.
因为我觉得你不会想守着个秘密
Because I thought that you didn't want to go to trial over...
受审
a secret.
我遇上一个老朋友
Then I caught up with an old friend,
看着她纠结于是否告诉家人她的秘密
and I watched as she struggled to tell her family hers,
因为她担心
because she was afraid...
家人知道真相后会不再爱她
that they wouldn't love her if they knew the truth.
不论你担心的是什么
Whatever you are worried about,
都不会减弱我们对你的爱
it will not make us love you any less.
你们不明白
You don't know.
你觉得你养育的是什么样的孩子
Who do you think you raised?
你教会我们坚强
You taught us to be strong.
我们可以战胜任何困难
That we could overcome any obstacle that we faced;
与之战斗
to fight.
你真的以为我们会轻易退缩吗
Do you really think that we are going to scare that easily?
不论发生什么
Whatever comes out...
你都不会失去我们
you won't lose us.
永远不会
Ever.
我会让简拒绝唐纳先生的辩诉交易
I'll instruct Jean to reject Mr. Donner's offer.
爸爸
Dad.
我知道我应该给你打电话
I know I owe you a phone call.
我有很多工作要做  我们能不能
I have a lot of work. Can we--
我们能不能下次再谈
can we do this another time?
我只想见见你  劳蕾尔
I just had to see you, Laurel.
发生了什么事吗  你还好吗
Did something happen? Are you ok?
总有一天  亲爱的
One day, honey,
当你有了自己的女儿
when you have a daughter of your own,
你会理解为人父母
you'll understand that being a parent,
意味着你永远都在担心自己的孩子
it means you just never stop worrying about your children.
爸爸  我很抱歉没有回你的电话
Dad, I'm--I'm sorry I didn't call you back.
我
I've--
我这周过得很累
I've had a really long week,
我很累
And--and I'm tired.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我不知道
I don't know.
我希望
I wish that there was--
发生一些事
there was something, a...
出现一切都好起来的迹象
a sign that it gets better.
会有的  亲爱的
It does, honey.
会好起来的
It gets better.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我希望我能告诉你  宝贝
I wish I could tell you, sweetie.
我也想告诉你
I wish I could tell you.
莎拉去哪了
Where's Sara?
她走了
She left.
你们没什么吧
You cool with that?
我没得选择
I didn't have much of a choice.
伏特加
一个老朋友给了我这个
An old friend gave this to me.
他说我会知道什么时候适合喝它
Said I would know when it was the right time to drink it.
现在是合适的时候吗
And now's the right time?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
但我要喝一杯
But I need a drink.
干杯
Prochnost.
这酒...
Hmm. That's...
你是对的
So you were right.
我通常是对的  奥利弗
Yeah, I usually am, Oliver.
什么事  说真的
About what, specifically?
无论我多么努力  狄格尔  我的过去
No matter how hard I try, Diggle, my past...
它并不想就此被掩埋
It doesn't want to stay buried.
我不想再努力尝试了
I don't want to try so hard anymore.
过去我经历的五年里
The five years that I was gone...
我并非一直待在岛上
I wasn't always on the island.
怎么是你
How are you--
败寇没有发言权
Prisoners do not speak.